(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-04T18:24:35.705313",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
U.M.R! ハイ!
U.M.R! Hey!
UMAじゃないよ うまる
Not UMA, I'm Umaru!
U.M.R! ハイハイ!
U.M.R! Hey hey!
UMAじゃないよ うまる
Not UMA, I'm Umaru!
いつだって全身全霊遊び倒せ
Always play with all your strength!
もっともっと楽しめよ乙女
Enjoy yourself more and more, maiden!
みんなに気づかれないように
So that nobody notices you,
いざ 行け! 干物妹ライフ
Now go! Himouto life!
お気に入りのフードかぶり
Wearing my favorite hood,
今日も今日とてゴロゴロして
Lounging around again today,
大好物のポテチを手にして
With my favorite potato chips in hand,
パソコンと睨めっこしよう
Let's have a staring contest with the PC!
立てば芍薬 座れば牡丹
A Chinese peony standing, a peony sitting,
歩く姿は百合の花
My walking form is a lily flower.
誰をもが羨む完璧JK
A perfect high-school girl everyone envies!
ほら玄関くぐったら変身だ! さあグータラしよう
Come home and transform! Let's be lazy!
いつだって “食う・寝る・遊ぶ” の三連コンボ
Always the "eat, sleep, play" 3-way combo!
ずーっとずーっとゲームは友達
Always, always, games will be my friends!
おにいちゃんは厳しいけれど
Big brother is strict,
きっときっと許してくくれるの
But he always, always forgives me!
わがまま放題は “大好き” の裏返し
Unlimited selfishness is the flip side of love!
U.M.R! ハイ!
U.M.R! Hey!
UMAじゃないよ うまる
Not UMA, I'm Umaru!
U.M.R! ハイハイ!
U.M.R! Hey hey!
UMAじゃないよ うまる
Not UMA, I'm Umaru!
外では猫をかぶり
Wearing a cat hood outside,
今日も明日も演じるのです
I'll pretend today and tomorrow too!
大好評の笑顔を武器に
Using my popular smile as a weapon,
友達にばれないように
So friends won't find out!
立てば二頭身 座ればまんまる
Short-bodied when standing, round when sitting,
歩く姿もちんちくりん
A tiny walking figure,
誰で癒せる愛敬マスコット!?
A cute mascot that heals anyone!?
さあ限界超えるまでパーティナイト!
Now, party night until we break the limits!
宴の始まりだ!
The party is starting!
可憐で優雅な女の子演じてみても
Even if I pretend to be a pretty and elegant girl,
おにいちゃんだけはだませない
The only person I can't fool is my big brother.
きらわれたくないもの
I don't want him to hate me.
素直に言えない “ありがとう” 態度で示そう
I can't say "thank you", so I'll show it with my attitude!
…だい! 全言撤回! ああもういいいいずい!!
...Oh well! Retract that! Forget it!!
立てばおっとりし 座ればまったり
Standing gracefully, sitting leisurely,
歩く姿はユリの花
My walking form is a lily flower,
誰もがうらやむ完璧ジェンケ
A perfect high-school girl everyone envies!
U・M・R! ハイ! U・M・R! ハイ!
U.M.R! Hey! U.M.R! Hey!
UMAじゃないよ うまる
It's not an UMA, it's Umaru!
U・M・R! ハイはい! U・M・R! ハイはい!
U.M.R! Hey, hey! U.M.R! Hey, hey!
UMAじゃないよ うまる
It's not an UMA, it's Umaru!
いつだって全身全霊遊び倒せ
Always play with all your strength and spirit!
もっと もっと 楽しめよ乙女
Enjoy yourself more and more, girl!
みんなに気づかれないように
So that no one notices,
いざ 行け! 干物妹ライフ
Okay, go! Himouto life!
お気に入りのフードかぶり
Wearing a hood 'cause I feel like it,
今日も今日とてゴロゴロして
lounging around again today,
大好物のポテチを手ニ
with my favorite food, potato chips in hand,
パソコンとにらめっこしよ
let's have a staring contest with the computer!
立てば芍薬 座れば牡丹
A Chinese peony when I stand, a tree peony when I sit,
歩く姿は百合の花
my walking form is a lily flower,
誰もが羨む完璧JK
a perfect high school girl everyone envies!
ほら玄関くぐったら変身だ! さあダラダラしよう♪
And when I come home I transform! Let's be lazy♪
いつも 「喰う! 寝る zzz 遊ぶ♪」の3連コンボ
Always the 3-way combo: eat, sleep, play♪
ずっと ずっと ゲームは友達
Always, always, games will be my friends,
お兄ちゃんは厳しいけれど
big brother is strict, but
きっと きっと 許してくれるのさ
he always, always forgives me!
わがまま放題は 「大好き」 の裏返し
Unlimited selfishness is the flip side of love.
U・M・R! ハイ! U・M・R! ハイ!
U.M.R! Hey! U.M.R! Hey!
UMAじゃないよ うまる
It's not an UMA, it's Umaru!
U・M・R! ハイはい! U・M・R! ハイはい!
U.M.R! Hey, hey! U.M.R! Hey, hey!
UMAじゃないよ うまる
It's not an UMA, it's Umaru!
U・M・R! UMAじゃないよ うまる
U.M.R! It's not an UMA, it's Umaru!
U・M・R! UMAじゃないよ うまる! Yeah!
U.M.R! It's not an UMA, it's Umaru! Yeah!
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for the unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
and embracing the unyielding wish.
ゆずれない
Unyielding...
願いを抱きしめて
...wish, holding it close.
ゆずれない願い
[Song: Yuzurenai Negai]
海の色が赤く染まっていく 無重力状態
The color of the sea is dyed crimson in free-fall,
このまま風にさらわれたい
I want to be swept away by the wind like this.
いつも跳べないハードルを
I've always cleared impossible hurdles
負けない気持ちで クリアしてきたけど
with a spirit that refuses to lose, but
出し切れない実力は 誰のせい?
whose fault is it that I still can't give my all?
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for the unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
and embracing the unyielding wish,
色褪せない心の地図 光にかざそう
I'll hold my unfading heart's map up to the light.
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for the unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
and embracing the unyielding wish,
色褪せない心の地図 光にかざそう
I'll hold my unfading heart's map up to the light.
どれだけ泣ければ 朝に出逢えるの
How much must I cry before meeting the morning?
孤独な夜 初めて限界を感じた日
The lonely night... the day I first felt my limits.
きっと恋に落ちるのは まばたきみたいな
Surely, falling in love is like a fleeting blink,
一瞬の情熱だけど
a momentary passion, but
愛に続く坂道で 強さを覚えたい
on the slope leading to love, I want to learn strength.
止まらない未来を夢見て
Dreaming of an unstoppable future,
口を閉ざし 瞳を光らせてきたけれど
I closed my lips and made my eyes gleam, but
もっと大きな 優しさが見えた
I was able to see a much greater kindness.
跳べないハードルを
Impossible hurdles
負けない気持ちで クリアしてきたけど
I've always cleared with a spirit that refuses to lose, but
スタートラインに立つたびに 怯えていた
whenever I stand at the starting line, I get scared.
止まらない未来を描いて
Sketching an unstoppable future,
腕を伸ばし 心を開いて
stretching out my arms and opening my heart.
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for the unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
and embracing the unyielding wish,
色褪せない心の地図 光にかざそう
I'll hold my unfading heart's map up to the light.
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for the unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
and embracing the unyielding wish,
色褪せない心の地図 光にかざそう
I'll hold my unfading heart's map up to the light.
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming at an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Embracing an unyielding wish,
海の色彩が紅く染まっていく
The sea colors are turning crimson,
無重力状態 このまま風にさらわれたい
In zero gravity, I want to be swept away by the wind.
いつも跳べないハードルを 負けない気持ちで クリアしてきたけど
Always facing hurdles I couldn't jump, clearing them with an undefeated spirit,
出し切れない実力は 誰のせい？
But whose fault is it that I can't give it my all?
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming at an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Embracing an unyielding wish,
色褪せない心の地図 光にかざそう
Holding up the unfading map of my heart to the light,
他の誰かになんてなれやしないよ
I'll never become anybody else,
そんなのわかってるんだ
I already know that.
明日を信じてみたいの
I want to try believing in tomorrow,
微かな自分を愛せなかったとしても
Even if I couldn't love my faint self.
Teenager Forever
望んだってすべてが叶うわけじゃないよ
Not everything I wished for will come true,
そんなのわかってるんだ
I already know that.
深い傷もいつかはかさぶたに変わって
Deep wounds will eventually turn into scabs
剥がれ落ちるだろうか
And peel off, won't they?
いつまでも相変わらずつまらない話を
Always telling the same boring stories,
つまらない中身にどこまでも幸せを探すよ
Searching endlessly for happiness within the boredom.
伝えたい想いは溢れているのに
My overflowing feelings want to be conveyed,
伝え方が分からなくて今でも言葉を探してるんだ
But I still don't know how, searching for words even now.
遠くに散っていった夢の欠片に
To the fragments of dreams scattered far away,
めくるめくあなたの煌めきに気づけたらいいんだ
It'd be nice if I could notice your dazzling sparkle.
Teenager Forever
結局のところ誰も教えてくれないんだ
In the end, no one will ever teach us,
進むべき道なんて
The path we should take.
等身大のままで生きていこうぜ 歳を重ねても
Let's live life as we are, even as the years pile up.
いつまでも相変わらずつまらない話を
Always telling the same boring stories,
つまらない中身にどこまでも幸せを探すよ
Searching endlessly for happiness within the boredom.
煌めきを探せよ
Search for that sparkle,
散々振り回して振り回されて
Being tossed around and tossed back and forth so much,
大切なのはあなただってことに気づけないままで
Without realizing that the most important thing is you.
一体未来はどうなるのかなんてことより
Rather than wondering what the future holds,
めくるめく今という煌めきに気づけたらいいんだ
It'd be nice if I could notice the dazzling sparkle of the present.
Teenager Forever
他の誰かになんてなれやしないよ
I'll never become anybody else,
そんなのわかってるんだ
I already know that.
明日を信じてみたいの
I want to try believing in tomorrow,
微かな自分を愛せなかったとしても
Even if I couldn't love my faint self.
突然降る夕立 あぁ傘もないやいや
A sudden evening shower, ah, I don't even have an umbrella, no way.
空のご機嫌なんか知らない
I don't care how the sky is feeling.
季節の変わり目の服は何着りゃいいんだろう
What am I supposed to wear at the change of seasons?
季節の変わり目の服は 何着りゃいいんだろ
When seasons change, what are you supposed to wear?
春と秋 どこいっちゃったんだよ
Spring and fall, where did they go?
息も出来ない 情報の圧力 めまいの螺旋
The pressure of information is suffocating, a dizzying spiral.
わたしはどこにいる
Where am I?
こんなに こんなに 息の音がするのに
Even though I can hear myself breathing so loudly,
変だね 世界の音がしない
it's strange, I can't hear the sounds of the world.
足りない 足りない 誰にも気づかれない
Not enough, not enough, no one notices me.
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed in a state where I couldn't even make a sound.
「ありのまま」なんて 誰に見せるんだ
"Just as I am"—who am I even showing that to?
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
A foolish girl like me can only sing.
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Shall I spill it all out to the stars?
エリクサーに張り替える作業も なんとなくなんだ
Even replacing my elixir strings feels somewhat meaningless.
欠けた爪を 少し触る
I gently touch my chipped nail.
半径300mmの体で必死に鳴いてる
My 300mm body is crying out desperately.
音楽にとっちゃ ここが地球だな
To music, this place is the Earth.
空気を握って 空を殴るよ
Grabbing the air, punching the sky—
なんにも起きない わたしは無力さ
nothing happens, I'm so powerless.
だけどさ その手で この鉄を弾いたら
But when you strum that steel with your hand,
何かが変わって見えた…ような。
it felt like something changed... maybe.
眩しい 眩しい そんなに光るなよ
Dazzling, dazzling, don't shine so bright!
わたしのダサい影が より色濃くなってしまうだろ
My uncool shadow will only stand out even more.
なんでこんな熱くなっちゃってんだ 止まない
Why am I getting so heated up? It won't stop.
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
A foolish girl like me can only sing.
うるさいんだって心臓
My heart is being so noisy.
蒼い惑星 ひとりぼっち
All alone on this pale blue planet,
いっぱいの音を聞いてきた
I've listened to countless sounds.
回り続けて 幾億年
Revolving for hundreds of millions of years,
一瞬でもいいから…ああ
even if just for a moment... ah.
聞いて 聴けよ わたし わたし わたしはここにいる
Listen, hear me! I, I, I am right here!
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed in a state where I couldn't even make a sound.
何者になりたい なりたい 何者かでいい
I want to be someone, anyone is fine.
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
A foolish girl like me can only sing.
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Shall I spill it all out to the stars?
とおい とおい むかしばなし
A distant, distant tale of old—
それは きっと あすのはなし
surely, it's a story of tomorrow.
“ もう 飛べ や し ない さ ”
"I can't fly anymore."
落ち続ける夜から覚めた 白い部屋の片隅で
Awoken from the endless falling night, in the corner of a white room,
彷徨ってる 自由をなくして
wandering about, having lost my freedom.
塞ぐ 倒れ込んだまま
Blocking my ears, collapsed right where I fell.
ああ 細い片翼が ああ ないんだ
Ah, my frail single wing—ah, it's gone.
叫んだ 心が止まらなくて
I screamed, my heart wouldn't stop racing.
機械みたいにきしむ僕を 現実が笑った
Reality laughed at me, creaking like a broken machine.
その時 誰かが囁いたんだ
In that moment, someone whispered to me:
「あなたにあげた つばさ」
"The wings I gave to you."
「あなたに あげた つばさ」
"I gave you wings,"
「わたしの ゆめみた せかい」
"The world I once dreamed of."
羽ばたきたい 大空 へ
I want to soar into the vast sky.
鳴呼 風が 呻く
Ah, the wind is wailing.
止まらないで 高く 高く へ
Don't stop — higher and higher,
幾度 夢 願い 祈った 雲 の 果て
past countless dreams and prayers, to the edge of the clouds.
終わり を 越えて 高く 高く へ
Beyond the end, higher and higher.
かけがえの ない ガラクタ の 羽 で
With irreplaceable, junk-like wings.
“星を見失った”
"I've lost sight of the stars."
紛れ住む 人間のセカイ
Living hidden in a human world,
一つの羽じゃ飛べない もう飛びたくない
I can't fly with just one wing — I don't want to fly anymore.
色彩の 半分だけで
With only half the colors,
底を這うこともできなかった
I couldn't even crawl at the bottom.
「わたしには もう いらないの」
"I don't need them anymore."
「かわりに ひかりは きみがみてよ」
"Instead, you see the light for me."
苛立つ ほどに 青かった エデンで 泣いていた
In the maddeningly blue Eden, I cried.
その時 掴んでくれた誰かの手 鳴呼
And then, someone's hand grabbed mine — ah.
あなたがくれた 希望で
With the hope you gave me,
約束の 羽で 今 飛ばなくちゃ
with the promised wings, I must fly now.
鳴呼 共に 往く 地平の 先へ
Ah, together we go, beyond the horizon.
壊れるまで 高く 高く へ
Until I'm broken, higher and higher,
今の僕は 片翼でいい
I'm okay with just one wing now.
飛べるよ 信じて 飛べるよ その先へ 飛べるよ
I can fly — believe it — I can fly, to what lies beyond.
楽園 永遠 の 彼方まで
I can fly, to paradise, to the eternity beyond.
きっと 不完全でも
Surely, even if I'm incomplete —
遥か 彼方 まで
Far, far beyond.
あの地平線 輝くのは
The horizon is shining
どこかに君を隠しているから
because it covers you somewhere.
たくさんの灯が なつかしいのは
Seeing many lights, I feel nostalgic
あのどれか一つに 君がいるから
because you are in one of them.
さあ 出かけよう ひときれのパンを
Now, let's go out with a piece of bread,
ナイフ ランプ かばんにつめこんで
a knife, a lamp packed in a bag.
父さんが残した 熱い想い
This burning will is what my father left me.
母さんがくれた あのまなざし
That gaze is what my mother gave me.
地球はまわる 君をかくして
The earth is turning around, covering you.
輝く瞳 きらめく灯
The eyes are shining, and the lights are glittering.
地球はまわる 君をのせて
The earth is turning around, carrying you.
いつかきっと 出会う ぼくらをのせて
Carrying us, who will surely meet one day.
あの水平線 輝くのは
The horizon shines
どこかに君を隠しているから
because it's hiding you somewhere.
たくさんの灯が 懐かしいのは
The reason I long for the many lights
あのどれかひとつに 君がいるから
is that you are there in one of them.
さあ出かけよう 一切れのパン
So, I set out, with a slice of bread,
ナイフ、ランプ 鞄に詰め込んで
a knife, a lamp, stuffed in a bag.
父さんが残した 熱い想い
Father left me his burning desire,
母さんがくれた あのまなざし
mother gave me her eyes.
地球は回る 君を隠して
The earth turns, hiding you.
輝く瞳 きらめく灯
Shining eyes, twinkling lights.
地球は回る 君をのせて
The earth turns, carrying you,
いつかきっと出会う ぼくらをのせて
carrying us both who'll surely meet.
父さんが残した 熱い想い
Father left me his burning desire,
母さんがくれた あのまなざし
mother gave me her eyes.
地球は回る 君を隠して
The earth turns, hiding you.
輝く瞳 きらめく灯
Shining eyes, twinkling lights.
地球は回る 君をのせて
The earth turns, carrying you,
いつかきっと出会う ぼくらをのせて
carrying us both who'll surely meet.
どっかー、あなたのルラノの歌
Laplus, your song...
めちゃめちゃ聴き入っちゃったよ。
I got so drawn into listening to it!
いや、まなさの歌もかっこよかったのだよ。
Well, Amane-san, your singing was cool too.
本当？じゃあ、そんな社交辞令も終わったところで、
Really? Well then, now that such polite flattery is out of the way,
どういうわけで、ホロ4期生ライブ皆さん楽しんでますか？
how is everyone enjoying the Hololive 4th Gen Live?
反応するところはここじゃー！これね、ガンガン盛り上がるんだな！
This is where you react! This gets you super hyped up!
はい、そしてこのステージ見てください！めちゃめちゃ綺麗だよね！
Yes, and look at this stage! It's so gorgeous, right?
これね、時間が経つと景色も変わっていくステージでございます。
This is a stage where the scenery changes as time passes.
え、朱鷺なの？チェックチェックしてください。さてさてお次の曲なんですが、
Eh, really? Check it out. Now then, for our next song...
ご趣味の方はいかがでしょうか？まあ、お任せするのだな。では、次の曲はこすりちらかした Get Wild！
Well, I'll leave it to you. So, the next song is our heavily overplayed Get Wild!
アスファルト タイヤを切り裂きながら
While cutting the asphalt tire
暗闇 走り抜ける
Run through the darkness
チープなスリルに身をまかせても
Even if you let yourself go for a cheap thrill
明日に怯えていたよ
I was scared of tomorrow
It's your pain or my pain or somebody's pain
誰かのために 生きられるなら
If you can live for someone
It's your dream or my dream or somebody's dream
何もこわくはない
I'm not scared of anything
Get wild and tough ひとりでは解けない 愛のパズルを抱いて
Get wild and tough - Embrace the love puzzle that can't be solved alone
Get wild and tough この街でやさしさに甘えていたくはない
Get wild and tough - I don't want to rely on kindness in this town
Get chance and luck 君だけが守れるものがどこかにあるさ
Get chance and luck - There is something that only you can protect
Get chance and luck ひとりでも傷ついた夢を取り戻すよ
Get chance and luck - I'll recover the damaged dream by myself
クルマのライトにキスを投げれば
Throw a kiss at the car lights
車道で踊るあの娘
That girl dancing on the road
冷たい夜空をステージにして
Use the cold night sky as a stage
悲しくおどけていたね
Acting playfully sad
It's your pain or my pain or somebody's pain
誰かのために 愛せるのなら
If you can love for someone
It's your dream or my dream or somebody's dream
きっと強くなれる
Surely become stronger
Get wild and tough ひとりでは消せない 痛みを心に抱いて
Get wild and tough - A pain that cannot be erased alone
Get wild and tough この街で自由を持て余したくはない
Get wild and tough - I don't want freedom in this city
Get chance and luck 君だけが守れるものがどこかにあるさ
Get chance and luck - There is something that only you can protect
アスファルト タイヤを切りつけながら
While cutting the asphalt tire
暗闇走り抜ける
Run through the darkness
チープなスリルに身をまかせても
Even if you let yourself go for a cheap thrill
明日におびえていたよ
I was scared of tomorrow
It's your pain or my pain or somebody's pain
誰かために生きられるなら
If you can live for someone
It's your dream or my dream or somebody's dream
何も こわくはない
I'm not scared of anything
Get wild and tough
ひとりでは解けない愛のパズルを抱いて
Embrace the love puzzle that can't be solved alone
Get wild and tough
この街でやさしさに甘えていたくはない
I don't wanna be kind to this town
Get chance and luck
君だけが守れるものがどこかにあるさ
There is something that only you can protect
Get chance and luck
ひとりでも 傷ついた夢を取り戻すよ
I'll recover the damaged dream by myself
Get wild and tough
ひとりでは解けない愛のパズルを抱いて
Embrace the love puzzle that can't be solved alone
Get wild and tough
この街でやさしさに甘えていたくはない
I don't wanna be kind to this town
Get chance and luck
君だけが守れるものがどこかにあるさ
There is something that only you can protect
Get chance and luck
ひとりでも 傷ついた夢を取り戻すよ
I'll recover the damaged dream by myself
いつだってそう「僕なんて」さって
Always thinking "Someone like me..."
うつむいてばっかりのMayday
Mayday, always hanging my head low
つまずいて泣いて
Stumbling and crying,
「どうせ」って口癖が染みついてさ
with "Whatever" as my catchphrase.
いつからかまた積もる焦り
Before I knew it, impatience kept piling up.
でも 胸の奥にある光
Yet deep within my heart, a light remains,
繋ぐ点と線の上
Connecting the dots and lines.
踏み出すイメージの先へ
Beyond the imagined steps we take,
遠くたっていい ほら 虹をまたいでさ
No matter how far, let's cross the rainbow!
さあ 心のままに 音を奏でる
Now, let your heart play its own sound!
逸る鼓動は 今を刻む証だ
Racing heartbeats are proof of the present moment.
響け 僕らの想いを乗せて
Ring out, carrying all our feelings,
高く遠く 歌を紡いで
Spinning a song high and far!
Lalala
季節巡って 駆け抜けて
Running through changing seasons,
気付けば大人になって
Before I knew it, I became an adult.
幼い日の心は 胸の奥くすぶってた
A child's heart still lingers deep inside.
怖いことも増えたけど
Though my fears have also grown,
でも 今だから見える世界
The world I can see right now is unique,
儚さの中に 確実に灯る光
A faint light glowing amidst the transient dream.
繋いでいこう さあ 新しいステージへ
Let's keep holding on, toward a new stage!
心の中の音を聴かせて
Let the music inside your heart play on!
大袈裟だっていい ありのままで自分だけで
Being dramatic is totally fine.
駆け抜けもっと いつまでもずっと 歌いながら
Burst forth even more, and sing forever,
日々を彩って
Painting the days with melody!
つまずいて泣いた日もあったけど
There were days of stumbling and crying,
涙も力になる
Even tears become our strength.
刻め HEART 鳴らせ BEAT
Engrave it, HEART! Ring it out, BEAT!
響け 僕らのメロディ
Echo, our melody!
ねえ あの日の夢も
Hey, those dreams of that day,
今の自分も 描く未来も
The current me, and the future I picture—
全て抱きしめるよ さあ 旅を続けよう
I'll embrace them all! Let's continue the journey!
どこまででもずっと 手を繋いで
Holding hands forever and ever,
ほら 僕らの一歩だ
Look, this is our first step!
心のままに 音を奏でる
Let your heart play its own sound,
いつだってそう「僕なんて」さって
Always saying things like "someone like me..."
蹲っていたばかりのmay day
On those cowering May Days.
つまずき泣いて「どうせ」って
Stumbling and crying, saying "oh well,"
口癖が染みついてさ
That catchphrase became second nature.
いつからかまた積もる焦り
Impatience has piled up again since when?
でも胸の奥にある光
But the light deep in my chest
繋ぐ点と線の上
Connects the dots and lines above.
踏み出すイメージの先へ
Beyond the image of stepping forward.
遠くたっていい
Even if it's far away,
ほら虹をまたいで
Look, striding across the rainbow,
さあ心のままに音を奏でる
Now, let's play our music straight from the heart.
逸る鼓動は今を刻む証だ
This racing heartbeat is proof of carving out the present.
響け僕らの想いを乗せて
Resonate, carrying our feelings!
高く遠く歌を紡いで
Weaving a song high and far away,
la la la...
本当は分かってた行けないことだったって分かってたのに
Truth is, I knew it wasn't right, even though I knew all along.
この手をすり抜ける全部愛に見えたの
Everything slipping through these hands looked like love.
確かめていた言葉が形になって揺れるだけ
The words I kept checking just take shape and waver.
弾いて描いてきっとそれだけ
Strumming and sketching, surely that's all there is.
つまらないな正解の読み合わせ
How boring, comparing our answers to the correct ones.
あとちょっとで分かりかけていたのに
Even though I was so close to figuring it out.
飲んで吐いて全部忘れちゃって
Drink, vomit, and forget everything,
水をまとった本心と鏡合わせ見つめ合えたら
Staring into true feelings clad in water as we face each other in the mirror.
overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us,
やるせない日々を
Through these frustrating days.
解像度の悪い夢を見たい
I want to dream a low-resolution nightmare.
overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us,
甘いハッタリ
A sweet bluff.
don't stop it music, darling
本当は分かってた行けないことだったって分かってる
Did you really know? I knew it wasn't right, yet I keep knowing.
多分時間だけが過ぎていく問答で満ちていく
Maybe only time is passing, filled with Q&As.
言い訳する間もなく裸になってしまうだけ
No time for excuses, I'm just left stripped bare.
きっと溜まっていくんだずっと終わってしまえばいいとふと
Surely it keeps piling up, wishing it would all just suddenly end.
傷んで腐っていくあの甘い果実のように僕ら壊れていく
Rotting and spoiling like that sweet fruit, we break apart.
だから踊って眠って全部忘れちゃって嘘を被ったあなたと隣り合わせ
That's why I dance, sleep, and forget all, side by side with you draped in lies.
見つめ合えたら
Once our eyes meet.
overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us,
分かりたいのに変に間の悪い嘘が嫌い
Even though I want to understand, I hate those awkwardly timed lies.
overdose 君とふたり分かりたいのに
Overdose, just the two of us, even though I want to understand.
two step from hell with me, darling
overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us,
やるせない日々を解像度の悪い夢を見たい
Through frustrating days, I want to dream a blurred nightmare.
overdose 君とふたり甘いハッタリ
Overdose, just the two of us, a sweet bluff.
don't stop it music, darling
overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us,
分からないけど変に間の悪い嘘でもいいから
I don't understand, but even awkwardly timed lies are fine, so
どうせ君とふたり甘いハッタリ
Just you and me, a sweet bluff.
don't stop it music, darling
はい、ということで、イェーイ！MCいきたいと思います！
Yes, and with that, yay! Let's move on to the MC segment!
じゃあ、1人じゃ寂しいので、はい！おいで、おいで！
Since being alone is lonely, come on over!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
みんな歌ったことあるのかな？
I wonder if everyone's sung this before?
MCはやっていきたいと思います！いぇーい！
Let's do the MC! Yay!
かっこよかったね、ありがとう！
That was so cool, thank you!
今日お互いのね、歌った曲に触れていきましょうか！
Let's talk about each other's songs we sang today!
はい、何歌ったんですか？
Yes, what did you sing?
私はね、ギターと孤独と青い星とOverdoseを歌わせていただきました！
I sang "Guitar and Loneliness and Blue Planet" and "Overdose"!
歌った歌った！
You sang them!
やめて、かっこよかったね！
Stop it, it was so cool!
Overdoseは流行りの曲、だからちょっと歌ってみて…
"Overdose" is a trendy song, so I tried singing it...
トワさんに合うよって選んでくれた曲を今回歌わせていただきました！
And this was the song chosen for me because it would suit me!
待ってたよ？
Waiting for us?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
確かに！
True!
歌いやすかった！
It was easy to sing!
おー！
Oh!
イエーイ！
Yeah!
ね、サイハイ！
Right, Saihi!
ありがとね！
Thank you!
で、わためが、わためはね？
And Watame, Watame...
インディジフォーエバーと合せstepを出させていただきまして！
...released "Indie-gi Forever" and "Awase Step"!
おー！
Oh!
合せstepめっちゃよかった！
"Awase Step" was so good!
嬉しい！これが新曲なんだけども、うん
I'm so glad! This is our new song, yeah.
今までの、私達が出してきた楽曲の歌詞が入ってたり、曲名が入ってたりする、この週年にぴったりの曲になってるんですよー！
It has lyrics and titles from the songs we've released so far,
making it the perfect song for this anniversary!
いや、そうなんだよ！トワ様リハーサルで聴いてて、すごい「エモい曲、いい曲だね」って言ったら
Yeah, exactly! When I listened to Towa-sama during rehearsal,
I thought, "What an emotional, great song."
歌詞とかね、はい、曲名が入ってらっしゃるっていうのを教えてもらったんで、もう先にちょっと味わっちゃいましたー！
She told me that the lyrics and song titles are included in it,
so I got to taste it a bit early!
でも、でもね！
But, but you know,
みんな味わえるんですよ、これ！
everyone gets to taste it too, you know!
え？なんですカ？
Eh? What is it?
この後？
After this?
なに？この合せstepの、なに？MVが、わためチャンネルで投稿されます！
What? The MV for this "Awase Step"
will be posted on Watame's channel!
なにー！？
What?!
反応いいな！
Such a good reaction!
気持ちいー！
Feels so good!
ありがてぇ、ありがてぇ
So grateful, so grateful.
ぜひ見てください！
Please check it out!
見てねー！
Watch it!
そして、そして！なんと、じゃじゃーん！ライブショー！
And, and! What's more, ta-da! Live show!
お互いデュエット初めてだね、初めてだね！
It's our first duet together, our first time!
ちょっとシナジーがあったんじゃない？このヒラヒラとか、確かにね！
Didn't we have some synergy? These frills and all, true!
ちょっとスクショタイムするか！
Let's do a screenshot time!
しようよ！
Let's do it!
あ、ポニーテールでね、ピースピース！
Ah, with ponytails, peace peace!
ピースピースだった？ピースピース、ハート？
Was it peace peace? Peace peace, heart?
あ、これ、ま、やって…おい！笑笑。やったところで！
Ah, this, well, do... Hey! Lol. Now that we did it!
えー、そうでしょう、我々なんと今日で…
Um, that's right, today we...
5周年！
5th anniversary!
5周年か！早いなあ
5th anniversary! Time flies.
いやもう5周年になっていたらもう我々はもうね、おっほねさんですから！
I mean, once it's 5 years, we're already seasoned veterans!
おっほねさん？
Seasoned veterans?
おっほねさんです！
Seasoned veterans!
5年ね、5ね…骨ね？骨さん!だってもう骨さんいっぱい入ってきたでしょ！
5 years, 5 ye... bones? Bone-san! Cause a lot of 'bones' have come in!
確かにね、もう中堅ぐらいになっちゃったよ
True, we're already around mid-tier.
ちょっともう、おばさんです笑笑
We're kind of old ladies already, lol.
いやいやいや、まだまだですよ！まだ、まだ！
No no no, not yet! Still, still!
じゃあちょっとちなみになんですけど、6年目に入るわけですよ。6年目の目標を聞いてもいいですか？
Well, by the way, we're entering our 6th year. Can I ask your goal for the 6th year?
いや、まだまだね、ピッチピチに、ね、若い子には負けねえぞっていう気持ちでね、がんばっていきたいと思います！
Well, we're still full of youth, and with the feeling of not losing to the young ones, we'll do our best!
おばさんやないか！
Aren't you just old ladies!
もう負けてるやないかピチピチって言ってる時点でね！
You're already losing the moment you say you're youthful!
自分がピチピチじゃないって言ってるやないか！ピチピチだよ！
You're saying you're not youthful! We are youthful!
そうだね、トワ様はなんかあるの？
That's right, does Towa-sama have anything?
そうですね、6年目は健康に暮らしたいですね
Well, in our 6th year, I want to live healthily.
おばさんやないか！
Aren't you an old lady!
あー苦しい！おばさんは言い過ぎた、ごめん！
Ah painful! 'Old lady' was going too far, sorry!
いや、でもでも大丈夫ですよ、全然、全然気にしてないですから
No, but it's totally fine, I'm not minding it at all.
そうだよね、うん
That's right, yeah.
もう言われ慣れてるから。おい！
I'm used to hearing it already. Hey!
気にしてるじゃん、おい！あ、ごめんごめん、すいません
You do mind, hey! Ah, sorry sorry, excuse me.
言われ慣れてんだよ。もうこんなもう
I'm used to it. Already like this,
次のおばあちゃんの曲いこうじゃん！一緒に歌うんでしょ？
Let's go to the next 'granny' song! We're singing together right?
そう、まだ待たないよ！
Right, don't wait yet!
そうだよ、そうだよ！
That's right, that's right!
じゃあちょっと次の曲、あのちょっと落ち着かして、落ち着かして、いきたいと思います。はい
Well then, let's calm down a bit for the next song and go. Yes.
一緒にタイトルコールしてね？
Let's do the title call together, okay?
はい！
Yes!
では、聞いてください！
Now, please listen!
メリーゴーランド！
Merry-go-round!
好きになるって どんな こと？ 新しい 自分に 会う こと
What is it like to fall in love?
It's meeting a new self
好きと 口に できなかった こと
Things I couldn't say I love you
貴方の 幸せ の 中、 私 が 居なかった こと
The fact that I wasn't in your happiness
それを 受け入れて しまった こと
The fact that I was able to accept that
一人 泣いていた バスタブ の 中
Crying alone inside the bathtub
顔 が 痛くて 貴方に 会いたくて
My face hurts, I want to see you
アイシテル を もう 何度 私、 口に した の だろ
How many times have I said "I love you"?
ななのに どうして 今 傍 に 誰も 居ない の
Yet why is there no one by my side now?
アイシテル って もう 何度 私 耳 に した の だろ
How many times have I heard "I love you"?
寂しさ だけ が この 胸 に 残って いる の です
Only loneliness remains in this chest
好きに なるって どんな こと
What is it like to fall in love?
いつだってそう「僕なんて」さって
Always telling myself, "A guy like me..."
俯いてばかりのMayday
A constant Mayday with my head bowed down.
つまづいて泣いて「どうせ」って口癖が染み付いてさ
Stumbling, crying, letting "oh well" become my habit.
いつからかまた積もる焦り
Before I knew it, impatience piled up again.
でも胸の奥にある光
But the light deep within my chest
繋ぐ点と線の上
connects the dots and lines above.
踏み出すイメージの先へ
Head beyond the image of stepping forward.
遠くたっていい ほら 虹をまたいで
It's okay if it's far, look, stepping across the rainbow.
さあ 心のままに音を奏でる
Now, play the music straight from the heart.
逸る鼓動は今を刻む証だ
This racing heartbeat proves we are marking the present.
響け 僕らの想いを乗せて
Resound, carrying our feelings,
高く遠く 歌を紡いで
spinning a song high and far.
la la la
季節巡って 駆け抜けて
Seasons pass, running through them,
気づけば大人になって
before I knew it, I became an adult.
幼い日の心は胸の奥すぶっすてた
The heart of my childhood was cast away deep inside.
怖いことも増えたけど
Things to fear increased as well,
でも今だから見え得る世界
but this is a world only visible now.
僅かの中に確かり灯る光
A light burning surely within the faintness—
繋いでいこう
let's keep connecting it.
さあ 新しいステージへ
Now, onto a new stage,
心の中の音を聴かせて
let me hear the sound inside your heart.
大袈裟だっていい
It's okay if it's exaggerated,
ありのままの自分で
just be your true self
咲き誇れもっと
and bloom more proudly,
いつまでもずっと
forever and ever.
歌いながら日々を紡いで
Spinning our days while singing.
俯いて泣いた日もあった
There were days I bowed my head and cried,
だけど涙も力になる
but even tears become strength.
刻め heart
Engrave your heart,
鳴らし beat
ring out the beat,
響け僕らのメロディ
resound our melody!
ねえ あの日の夢も
Hey, the dream of that day,
今の自分も 描く未来も
my current self, and the future I draw—
全て抱きしめるよ
I will embrace it all.
さあ 旅を続けよう
Now, let's continue the journey
どこまでもずっと 手を繋いで
holding hands forever wherever we go.
ほら 僕らの1歩だ
Look, it's our first step.
さあ 眠眠打破 昼夜逆転 VOX AC30W
Now, breaking drowsiness, day-night reversal, VOX AC30W.
テレキャスター背負った サブカルボーイがバンド仲間にやっほー
A subculture boy with a Telecaster says "Yahoo" to his bandmates.
アルバイトはネクラモード 対バンにはATフィールド
Part-time job in gloomy mode, an AT field for joint gigs.
“人見知り”宣言で逃げる気か boy
Planning to run away by declaring yourself "shy," boy?
ゆーて お坊っちゃんお嬢ちゃん お金も才能も
Come on, little lord and lady, money and talent—
なまじっかあるだけ厄介でやんす
having them just makes things troublesome.
Boys be ambitious... (はいはい) like this old man
Boys be ambitious... (yes, yes) like this old man.
長い前髪 君誰の信者 信者 信者
Long bangs, whose believer are you, believer, believer?
勘違いすんな 教祖はおまえだ
Make no mistake, the cult leader is you.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki's rock 'n' roll,
かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは don't stop! don't stop!
strumming the electric guitar, don't stop! don't stop!
さあ 君のすべてを曝け出してみせろよ
Now, bare everything you are and show it to me.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki's rock 'n' roll,
さあ 日進月歩 いい曲書いてる? 動画ふえてる?
Now, daily progress—writing good tunes? videos increasing?
「知名度あるけど 人気はそんなにないから色々大変ですね。」
"You have fame, but not that much popularity, so things are tough."
はっきり言うなよ 匿名アイコン
Don't say it so clearly, anonymous icon.
はっきり見せない 写真のアイコン
Never showing clearly, profile photo icon.
いい歳こいて 自意識未だ boy
Acting grown yet still full of self-consciousness, boy.
ぶっちゃけんどんだけ 賢くあざとくやったって
Frankly, no matter how smartly and cunningly you play,
10年後に メイクは落ちてんだろう
your makeup will wear off in 10 years.
Boys be ambitious... (はいはい) like this old man
Boys be ambitious... (yes, yes) like this old man.
生き抜くためだ キメろ take a "selfy" "selfy" "selfy"
It's to survive, strike a pose, take a "selfy" "selfy" "selfy".
死ぬんじゃねえぞ お互いにな!
Don't you dare die on me, let's both survive!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki's rock 'n' roll,
薄っぺらいラブソングでもいい don't stop! don't stop!
even a shallow love song is fine, don't stop! don't stop!
さあ 目の中のあの子を撃ち抜いてみせろよ
Now, try to shoot through that girl in your eyes.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki's rock 'n' roll,
お茶を濁してちゃ 満足できない
You can't be satisfied just beating around the bush.
さあ 睡眠打破 昼夜逆転
So wake up, break sleep, day and night reversed.
VOX AC30W
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイが バンド仲間にやっほー
The subculture boy with a Telecaster says hello to his bandmates
アルバイトはネクラモード 対バンドにはATフィールド
Part-time job is gloomy mode, AT field against other bands
“人見知り”宣言で逃げる気か boy
Planning to run away by declaring you're "shy", boy?
ゆーて お坊っちゃんお嬢ちゃん お金も才能も なまじっかあるだけ厄介でやんす
Well, little lord and lady, having just enough money and talent is just a nuisance
boys be ambitious...
（はいはい）
(Yeah, yeah)
like this old man
長い前髪 君誰の信者 信仰 信仰 勘違いすんなよ 教祖はオマエだ
Long bangs, whose follower are you? Believe! Make no mistake, you are the cult leader
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは don't stop! don't stop!
Roki-roki rock 'n' roll, strumming the electric guitar, don't stop! don't stop!
さあ 君の全てを 暴き出してみせろよ
Come on, try exposing your everything
baby baby baby
baby baby baby baby baby
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは
Roki-roki rock 'n' roll, strumming the electric guitar
don't stop! don't stop! さあ 君の全てを
Don't stop! Don't stop! Come on, your everything
暴き出してみせろよ ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Expose it and show me, roki-roki rock 'n' roll
死ぬんじゃねぇぞ お互いにな！ 死に金のわざ お互い様
Don't you dare die, both of us!
みんな、4期生5周年記念ライブ見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone for watching the 5th Anniversary Live!
最後に5周年の記念グッズのお知らせです。今回は「式」をテーマにしたグッズになっています。
Now, here is our 5th anniversary merch, themed around ceremonies.
すでにイラストがイイ感じ！ということでそれでは一つずつ見ていきましょう！
The illustrations are already great! Let's check them out!
まずはこちら、アクリルジオラマスタンド（全4種）。背景付きのアクリルジオラマなので、迫力満点！
Acrylic Diorama Stands (4 types). Super impactful with backgrounds!
春夏秋冬でつながるイラストなので4期生みんな並べて飾ってちょー！よろしくお願いいたします！
They connect across seasons, so display them all together!
さあ次のグッズはルナ！…はーい！次のグッズはこちらなのだー！ででーん！
Next up is Luna! The next item is right here, ta-da!
ランダム缶バッジなのだー！全部で8種類の中からランダムで1種類入っていまーす。
Random Can Badges! One of 8 types included at random.
アンダーホログラムという仕様で、名前の部分がキラッと光る仕様らしいなら。
With an under-hologram design where the names glimmer.
そして今回、あなたの衣装はとっても清楚で可愛らしいまさに「春」って感じなので、ぜひぜひみんな手に入れてなのだー！
Kanata's outfit is so pure and spring-like, get yours!
次はわためちゃ、よろしくなのだー！
Next is Watame-cha, take it away!
はーい！ではではお次はスマホショルダーバッグです！春夏秋冬問わず使えるスポーティーなスマホショルダーは透明窓付きなので、お気に入りのグッズを見せることができます！
Sporty shoulder bags with a transparent window to show off goods!
アクスタや缶バッジを収納して推しアピールしちゃいましょう！
Store standees or badges to rep your Oshi!
お次はトワっち！はーい、わためから引き継ぎました！こよぴー！
Towa-cchi! Handed over from Watame, Koyopii!
次はこちら、マルチケース！イェーイ！
Next is the Multi Case! Yay!
イヤホンや缶バッジを入れてバッグにつけて推しと一緒に お出かけ気分に！ということでもトワたちを入れていろんなとこに出かけて写真をポストしてね！
Put in earphones or badges and take your Oshi everywhere!
そして最後はこちら、じゃじゃーん！ブロマイドケース！なんと、みんなの複製手書きメッセージステージ入りです！アルバムのような形でコレクション性があるグッズとなっております。
Bromide Case! Includes handwritten replicated messages like an album.
ということで、どうでしたか？どのグッズも素敵だったと思いませんか？ということで皆さんぜひ買ってくださーい！
Aren't they wonderful? Everyone, please be sure to buy them!
ご購入については概要欄のリンクやXをチェックしてみてください。
Check the description links or X for purchase details.
ではでは皆さん、次の配信でお会いしましょう！以上、4期生からでした！バイバーイ！
See you in the next stream! That's all from 4th Gen, bye-bye!